resumehelp.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy | ResumeHelp

##  Effective Date: February 8, 2016

This Privacy Policy explains RBK Global sarl and Hiring Products (“Merchant,” “we” or “us”) online information practices and the choices you can make about the collection and use of information you submit or we collect through our website www.hiringproducts.com, and our other related mobile websites, mobile applications (“mobile apps”), services, tools, and other applications (the “Site”).

The Site is owned and operated by Merchant.

By using the Site you expressly consent to the practices described in this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) and the [User Agreement](https://www.resumehelp.com/user-agreement.aspx). Merchant provides an online destination for help with resumes, cover letters, important career decisions and more! We do not guarantee employment for any user of this Site. Nor do we guarantee that any employer will find qualified candidates through this Site. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, “personal information” means information about an identifiable individual

When you use the Site, you are contracting with Merchant. If you reside outside of the United States Merchant is your data controller. By using the Site, you expressly consent to our collection, use, disclosure, and retention of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

##  Privacy Policy Summary

Your privacy is very important to the Merchant. The Privacy Policy is divided up into five (5) key functions.

  * **Information We Collect**
  * **Uses and Retention of Information**
  * **User Choices & Obligations**
  * **Important Information**
  * **Tracking Technologies**

##  1.Information We Collect

We collect the following information when you use the site

###  (a) Registration, Product and Account Information:

You can browse the Site without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information (i.e., name, email address, phone number, mobile telephone number, credit card information, physical contact information) about yourself. If you register for an account with us or use some of our products and services you choose to give us your personal information and are not anonymous to us. When you register an account or use our products and services, create a profile, create a resume, search purchase products, or otherwise engage with our Site, you may provide personal information. Personal information is only associated with your account/profile when you sign in as a registered user. With your consent, your email account messages may be reviewed by us.

###  (b) Information to respond to your requests

You may give us your personal information so we can respond to your questions and requests as well as send you newsletters and other communications you request. Details of how you can opt-out of receiving any communications from us are detailed in the section headed Accessing, Reviewing, and Changing Your Personal Information below.

###  (c) Social Media Information 

We may offer sign-on services that allow you to use third-party login credentials to access the Site. We also may offer services that allow you to share information with third-party social media websites such as Facebook, Google Plus, Twitter, and others.

When you link your account or engage with our Site through third-party social media sites, you understand that you may be allowing us to have ongoing access to certain information stored on those social media sites (e.g., your social networking credentials, your public profile, friend list, photos, people you follow or who follow you, your email address, birthday, work history, education history, interests, current city, religious and political views, website, personal description, and likes, and your friends’ birthdays, education histories, personal descriptions and likes). We may also receive other information (e.g., content viewed and information about the advertisements within the content you have been shown or may have clicked on, etc.) from your interaction with our Site. You agree that we may share your video viewing with or obtain information about your video viewing from analytics providers and advertising partners, third-party partners and social media sites for two years or until you withdraw your consent. The information we have access to from the third-party social services varies by service and is controlled by your privacy settings on that service and by your consent. Information that may be passed to analytics providers and advertising partners may be via cookies and tracking technologies. Please see our [ Cookies and Tracking Technologies Policy ](https://www.resumehelp.com/cookie-tracking-technologies-policy.aspx) for information, including your choices in relation to some of these technologies. By associating an account managed by a third party with your Merchant account and authorizing us to have access to this information, you agree that we may collect, use, and store information from these websites in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

###  (d) Information About Others/Inviting Friends

From time to time you may choose to submit personal information about other people to invite them to join Merchant . Inviting friends is always optional.

###  (e) Information From Other Sources 

The information we collect may be combined with information from outside public records (e.g., demographic information, navigation information, additional contact information) that we have acquired in accordance with the law.

###  (f) Information You Post On or Through the Site

The posting sections of the Site give you an opportunity to provide us with information regarding yourself (e.g., education level, degree or career course of interest, career objectives, employment history, resume, job descriptions) or opinions and reviews of our products and services. Also your profile may contain a photograph or other information that identifies you. In addition, the content you post, and recommendations you make may provide information about your beliefs to us.

### (g) Technical Usage Information

When you visit our Site, we collect usage information sent to us by your computer, mobile, or other access device that tells us how you are using the Site including video-viewing ("usage information"). We use tracking technologies (including [ cookies](https://www.resumehelp.com/cookie-tracking-technologies-policy.aspx#d1), [flash cookies](https://www.resumehelp.com/cookie-tracking-technologies-policy.aspx#d1), [web beacons/GIFs](https://www.resumehelp.com/cookie-tracking-technologies-policy.aspx#d2), [ embedded scripts](https://www.resumehelp.com/cookie-tracking-technologies-policy.aspx#d3)) to collect usage information. We may use tracking technologies for a variety of purposes, including:

**Operationally-Necessary.** We may use tracking technologies required for system administration, to prevent fraudulent activity, improve security or allow you to make use of shopping cart functionality. We are not required to obtain your consent to tracking technologies that are operationally necessary.

**Performance-Related.** We may use cookies or other tracking technologies to assess the performance of the online services, including as part of our analytic practices to improve the content offered through the online services.

**Functionality-Related.** We may use tracking technologies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited the Site before or if you are a new visitor and to help us identify the features in which you may have the greatest interest.

**Targeting-Related.** We may use tracking technologies to deliver content, including ads, relevant to your interests on our online service and third-party sites based on how you interact with our advertisements or content as well as track the content you access (including video viewing). Further information on this, and your [ opt-out choices](https://www.resumehelp.com/cookie-tracking-technologies-policy.aspx#s4) , is below.

We may also collect password information from you when you log in, as well as computer and/or connection information. During some visits we may use software tools to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, time spent on certain pages and page interaction information. 

Our goal is to collect and use only that information that we think is required for our legitimate business interests, in order to better understand your interests and improve your experience of using the Site. You consent to our tracking of your video viewing through the Site for up to two years or third party social media. To learn more about how we use tracking technologies and cookies, see  Section 5 of this Privacy Policy and [ click here.](https://www.resumehelp.com/cookie-tracking-technologies-policy.aspx)

##  2\. Use and Retention of Information

We want to be clear how we use your information and the manner in which that information is retained.

###  (a) Use and Retention

  1. **Operate Our Site and Provide You With Our Services:** We use the personal information we collect including email accounts you might create on our platform to: (1) respond to your questions and requests; (2) provide customer service (e.g., to fulfill product and service orders made by you, give you information about your account to resolve disputes, problems with your account/profile or the Site); (3) personalize your experience by providing content on the Site, including targeted advertising, that we believe may be of most interest to you; (4) improve the Site; and (5) provide you with a safe, efficient, and customized experience.
  2. **Analyze and Aggregate Non-Personal Information:** We use aggregate information about our users and non-personal information to analyze Site and user behavior and prepare aggregated reports.
  3. **Prevent Fraud:** We use information from the Site to prevent, detect, and investigate fraud, security breaches, and potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce our [User Agreement](https://www.resumehelp.com/user-agreement.aspx).
  4. **Communicate With You and Third Parties at Your Request:** We use your information to contact you to maintain the Site, your account, or to comply with your stated communication preferences, or to provide other products or services requested by you, as described at the time when we collect the information from you, or to contact you for other purposes authorized by law. If you have chosen to participate in some of our career building Services, the information you share with us may be provided to third parties including, but not limited to, resume editors, employers or recruiters who might contact you about career opportunities, employers seeking candidates and/or other career service providers.
  5. **Mobile Data:**

When you access the Site on a mobile device, with your consent as obtained through your use of the Site we may use the information collected for any purpose set forth in this Privacy Policy. For example, we may use this information to provide you with location-based services, such as advertising, search results, and other personalized content.

We retain personal information for as long as it is necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for which it was collected and to comply with the applicable laws and you consent to such purpose(s) remains valid after termination of our relationship with you. You consent to our retention of your video viewing tracking data for as long as permissible under applicable law – up to one year after you close your account or otherwise withdraw consent for video tracking.

###  **(b) Disclosure**

Information on the Site might be shared with:

  1. **The Merchant Corporate Family and Other Third Parties.** We may share the information we collect about you with the Merchant corporate family (our affiliates as well as with third party suppliers. The information may be disclosed: (1) to provide joint content and our products and services (e.g., registration, transactions, analytics and customer support); (2) to help detect and prevent potentially illegal acts, violations of our policies, fraud and/or data security breaches; and (3) to guide decisions about our, Merchant or third party’s products, sites, applications, services, tools, and communications. Members of our corporate family will use this information to send you marketing communications and you will have the opportunity to opt-out in email communications.
  2. **Other Entities with your Consent.** We may share your personal information with third parties to whom you explicitly ask us to send your information (or about whom you are otherwise explicitly notified and consent to when using a specific service). On the Site, you may have opportunities to express interest in or register for other products and services. If you do, we will provide information about you to those third parties, or parties working on their behalf, to implement your request.
  3. **Service Providers and Other Third Parties.** We may disclose your information to service providers under contract who help with our business operations (such as, but not limited to, fraud investigations, bill collection, payment processing, and site [analytics and operations](https://www.resumehelp.com/cookie-tracking-technologies-policy.aspx#d3) ) These service providers are prohibited from using your personal information for any purpose other than to provide this assistance and are required to protect personal information collected by them on behalf of Merchant or disclosed to them by us and to comply with the general privacy principles described in this Privacy Policy.
  4. **Ad Networks.** On the Site, we may work with third parties to serve advertisement, provide us with data collection, reporting, ad response measurement and site analytics and assist with delivery of relevant marketing messages and advertisements. These third parties may view, edit or set their own tracking technologies/cookies. The use of these technologies by these third parties is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by this Privacy Policy. They might also obtain information about other applications that you have downloaded to your mobile device, the mobile websites you visit and other information about you or your device in order to analyze and serve anonymous targeted advertising on the Site and elsewhere. For more information about third party ad servers at our Site and your ability to opt-out of targeted advertising from such third parties, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> which provides information about certain companies. 
  5. **Change of Control - New Owners.** Other business entities, should we plan to merge with or be acquired by that business entity. Should such a combination occur, we will make reasonable efforts to request that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information. If your personal information would be used contrary to this policy, you will receive prior notice and depending on the circumstances, an opportunity to opt-in to or opt-out of the new use.
  6. **Companies In the Mobile App Industry.** If you access the Site through a mobile device or app, we may also share your information with Carriers, operating systems and platforms.
  7. **Legal and Law Enforcement.** Law enforcement, governmental agencies, or authorized third parties, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity or any other activity that may expose us, you, or any other Merchant user to legal liability. In such events, we will only disclose information relevant and necessary to the investigation or inquiry, such as name, city, state, ZIP code, telephone number, email address, user ID history, IP address, fraud complaints, and anything else we may deem relevant to the investigation.

###  **(c) Communication Preferences and Marketing (Opt out)**

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your consent. We may combine your information with information we collect from other companies and use it to improve and personalize the Site. If you do not wish to receive marketing communications from us, you can indicate your communications preference within the direct communication from us or through your account/profile settings. You may not opt-out of administrative emails (for example, emails about your transactions or policy changes) or promotional messages by clicking the “My Account” tab and clicking the “My Settings” and “Preferences” tabs. You may also click the unsubscribe link in the footer of any email or newsletter you receive for your registered account.

###  **(d) Third Parties**

Our Site may contain links to other third party websites and Merchant may provide products and services that share information with third party sites for your job search. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these third party sites so it is important to familiarize yourself with their privacy policies before providing personal information. 

For more information about the use of cookies and similar technology on our online services please review this Privacy Policy and our [ Tracking Technologies Policy](https://www.resumehelp.com/cookie-tracking-technologies-policy.aspx).

##  3\. User Choices and Obligations

###  **(a) Accessing, Reviewing, and Changing Your Personal Information**

Registered members can review and change personal information at any time by accessing their accounts on the Site (through the [My Accounts](https://www.resumehelp.com/user/settings.aspx) and [My Settings](https://www.resumehelp.com/user/settings.aspx)). You should promptly update your personal information if it changes or becomes inaccurate. We may retain some information from closed accounts so that we can comply with law, prevent fraud, assist with investigations, resolve disputes, analyze or troubleshoot programs, enforce our User Agreement, or take other actions permitted by law. Likewise if your account or membership is terminated or suspended, we may maintain some information to prevent re-registration. For non-registered members, you may update or request to access your personal information by contacting us as set forth in the How to Contact US section below.

We will endeavor to comply with your requests as soon as reasonably possible but please note that changes requested of us may not be effective immediately. Unless required by law, we are not responsible for informing third parties (including without limitation our third party service providers, potential employers, job-posting sites you authorize us to contact on your behalf, or strategic or marketing partners) with whom we have already shared your information of any changes requested pursuant to this section, or for removing information from or causing information to be removed from the databases or records of such entities.

###  **(b) Security**

We maintain technical, physical, and administrative security measures to protect the security of your personal information against loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure copying, use or alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls, data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers and information access authorization controls. It is your responsibility to make sure that your personal information is accurate. 

##  4\. Important Information

###  **(a) Children's Privacy**

The Site is a general audience site and it is not intended for children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information via our websites, applications, services, or tools from users in this age group.

If you are a minor and want to remove the information you posted to the Site, please contact us via the email or mailing address listed in the How to Contact us  section below. Removal of the information you posted does not ensure its complete or comprehensive removal.

###  **(b) International Transfer**

As we operate internationally, and many of our computer systems are currently based globally, for the purpose set out in this Privacy Policy your personal information may be stored and processed in the U.S. and elsewhere by us, our affiliates or an unaffiliated service provider. The data protection and privacy regulations may not offer the same level of protection as in other parts of the world, such as the European Union. When you create an account/profile or otherwise provide us with personal information, you consent to the collection, storage and/or processing of your personal information in the United States and other countries of your personal information and tracking technologies/cookies as described in this Policy.

###  **(c) Notification Regarding Updates to this Privacy Policy.**

From time to time, we may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in legal or regulatory obligations or changes in the manner in which we deal with personal information. The Privacy Policy posted at any time or from time to time via this Site shall be deemed to be the Privacy Policy then in effect. You agree that we may notify you about material changes in the way we treat personal information by placing a notice on the Site. You should check the Site frequently for updates.

###  **(d) Notice to California Residents**

Residents of the State of California may request a list of all third parties to which our online service has disclosed certain personal information (as defined by California law) during the preceding year for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and want such a list, please contact us at [californiarequest@hiringproducts.com](mailto:californiarequest@hiringproducts.com). For all requests, you must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the body of your request, as well as your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. In the body of your request, please provide enough information for us to determine if this applies to you. You need to attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for our response. Please note that we will not accept requests via the telephone, mail, or by facsimile, and we are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or that do not have complete information

Merchant does not currently take actions to respond to Do Not Track signals as a uniform technological standard has not yet been developed. We continue to review new technologies and may adopt a standard once one is created.

##  5\. Tracking Technologies (Cookies)

Tracking tehcnology used to enhance your online experience.

###  **(a) Tracking Technologies (Cookies)**

When you visit the Site, we and our business partners may use tracking technologies to enhance your online experience or customize our offerings. A few additional important things you should know about our use of tracking technologies (cookies): 

  1. We offer certain features that are available only through the use of tracking technologies.
  2. We use both session and persistent tracking technologies. Tracking technologies (e.g., cookies) can either be persistent (i.e., they remain on your computer until you delete them) or temporary (i.e., they last only until you close your browser). You are always free to decline tracking technologies if your browser permits, although doing so may interfere with your use of the Site. Refer to the help section of your browser, browser extensions, or installed applications for instructions on blocking, deleting, or disabling tracking technologies such as cookies.
  3. We encode and protect the tracking technologies that Merchant sets, so that only we can interpret the information stored in them.
  4. You may encounter tracking technologies/cookies from our third party service providers, that we have allowed on our Site that assist us with various aspects of our Site operations and services, such as [ Google Analytics](https://www.resumehelp.com/cookie-tracking-technologies-policy.aspx#s3).
  5. You also may encounter tracking technologies from third parties on certain pages of the websites that we do not control and have not authorized. (For example, if you view a web page created by another user, there may be a cookie placed by that web page).
  6. We may target and track the videos you view on the Site. You consent to our tracking of your video viewing through the Site or third party social media for up to two years or as permitted by applicable law.

**For more information about the use of cookies and similar technology on our online services please review this Privacy Policy and our[ Tracking Technologies Policy.](https://www.resumehelp.com/cookie-tracking-technologies-policy.aspx)**

###  **How to Contact Us**

**If your questions were not adequately answered in this Privacy Policy you may email Merchant at[privacy@hiringproducts.com](mailto:privacy@hiringproducts.com) or using the [contact us](https://www.resumehelp.com/contact-us.aspx) form on the Site.** You may also contact us by writing to our office at RBK Global sarl, 37A, Boulevard J-F Kennedy, L‑1855 Luxembourg.
